<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<language id="44">

<!-- Naming Schemne: 5554 -> Hexadecimal Ascii for UT; 
20 for Object/Map related things; 
1 for Galaxy-like things (there will be probably none); 2 for Clusters; 3 for sectors; 4 for Zones; 5 for Stations; 6 for Ships; 7 for Drones; 8 for unique things
t-ids under this use the following number Scheme:
thousands are groupings for the Project
tens and hundreds are IDs inside this grouping
and for the ones: 1 is for the Object Name, 2 is for the Object description, 3 is for a Short Variation in Caps, 4 is for Shortvariation in CamelCase (often same as 3) -->

<page id="5554203" title="Sectors by UniTrader" descr="Text for Sectors" voice="yes" pico2wave-options="">
 <t id="1011">Behind Rupture</t>
 <t id="1012">Behind Rupture is a Sector which has been integrated in the Albion Highway-system just recently - this new connection opened many new Buisness Opportunites, but also increased Pirate Activity in the whole of Albion for unknown Reasons. Before the connection of this Sector you had to travel several Days to reach this Ressourceful Region.</t><!-- a Sector which has been just recently integrated into the Albion Highway System; before that you had to travel for weeks to reach this Region rich of Minerals - the new Connections gave rise to new Buissness oppttunites, but also raised Pirate Activities in the whole of Albion according to rumors -->
 <t id="1013">BR</t>
 <t id="1014">BR</t>
</page>

<page id="5554204" title="Zones by UniTrader" descr="Text for Zones" voice="yes" pico2wave-options="">
 <t id="1011">Bealsio</t>
 <t id="1012">The escalating Conflict between Plutarch and Heart of Albion put the Stations of Berryl in Ascension often into the Crossfire and they were often heavily damaged by this, therefore the Corporate Managment decided to move their Headquarters out of the Conflict Area into this Zone. Because of the plentiful Ressources in this Zone people say the Asteroids here are filled with Berryls.</t><!-- new HQ for Berryl; Region is rich of Silicon, Crystals etc. (people say the Asteroids here are filled with Berryls) -->
 <t id="1013">BAS</t>
 <t id="1014">Bas</t>
 <t id="1021">Passage</t>
 <t id="1022">For unknown reasons the dense Asteroid Fields in this Area form some kind of Tunnel the tubes were planned in such a way that they go straight through this Tunnel to save costs for clearence of the Area. Additionally the Path from Flowstones to this Zone is said to be the most safe in the whole of Albion because Pirate Attacks are very seldom here.</t><!-- Exit Zone to Lookout Alpha; Asteroids around this Zone and the local Highway there create a Tunnel; the Path from Flowstones to this Zone is considered pretty safe by Pilots because here are the fewest Pirate attacks in the whole Albion System -->
 <t id="1023">PAS</t>
 <t id="1024">Pas</t>
 <t id="1031">Flowstones</t>
 <t id="1032">This is the Entry to Behind Rupture from the inner Albion-Sectors. This Zone got its Name from the Hydrogen/Ice-stream which "flows" through here. The reson for the formation of such a field is undetermined, but its very interesting to look at.</t> <!-- Entry Zone to the Behind Rupture System; Ice Asteroids create something which looks like a River here -->
 <t id="1033">FLS</t>
 <t id="1034">Fls</t>
 <t id="1041">Erosion</t>
 <t id="1042">An insignificant Zone, whichs most outstanding attribute are the unusual, Splittered Asteroids. Many Travelers report they had a bad feeling when traversing this Zone.</t><!-- nothing significant, most notable feature of this Zone are the Asteroids which look like they are Broken/Eroded (planned) - later this Zone will be an Entry Point for Xenon Forces (planned for even later) -->
 <t id="1043">ERS</t>
 <t id="1044">Ers</t>
 <t id="1051">Stalagtites</t>
 <t id="1052">Stalagtites Description</t><!-- small Ice Droplets flow through this Zone and it also has many smaller Asteroids -->
 <t id="1053">ST</t>
 <t id="1054">St</t>
 <t id="1061">Stalagmites</t>
 <t id="1062">Stalagmites Description</t><!-- similar to the former, located almost directly beneath it-->
 <t id="1063">SM</t>
 <t id="1064">Sm</t>
 <t id="1071">Shaft</t>
 <t id="1072">Similiar to Passage the Asteroid here are forming a Tunnel, but in opposite to that one the Tunnel goes straight down instead of parallel to the Zone Ecliptic, therefore the Name of the Zone.</t><!-- a simple passthrough Zone; also has an Asteroid Tunnel like Passage, although it goes straight down, therefore the Name -->
 <t id="1073">SHF</t>
 <t id="1074">Shf</t>
 <t id="1081">Pit</t>
 <t id="1082">The Deepest Zone in the whole of Albion - Travellers feel very lost, like lookint into an Abyss.</t><!-- the Bottommost Zone in the Sector; you will feel very lost here, like when staring into an Abyss - later this Zone will contain an Exit Gate to another new Sector (planned) -->
 <t id="1083">PIT</t>
 <t id="1084">Pit</t>
 <t id="1091">Hidden Chamber</t>
 <t id="1092">A Zone occupied by Pirates of the Sorveign Syndicate, which contains a small, heavy armed Shipyard which was constructed from Pirated Parts to maintain Pirate Ships. The towed broken Asteroid Parts are disguising the Installation from the Radars of the Police and the Military and reduce the movemant ability of Capital Ships in the case of an engagement. When you dont know where to look the chance of finding this Zone is nonexistent.</t><!-- a Pirate Sector which contains a small Shipyard which is hevily armed; you have to know where to look if you want to find this Zone -->
 <t id="1093">HC</t>
 <t id="1094">HC</t>
</page>

<page id="5554208" title="Unique Names by UniTrader" descr="Text for Unique Objects" voice="yes" pico2wave-options="">
 <t id="1011">Sorveign Syndicate Shipyard</t>
 <t id="1012">A Shipyard which was constructed from Pirated Parts to maintain Pirate Ships. The towed broken Asteroid Parts are disguising the Installation from the Radars of the Police and the Military and reduce the movemant ability of Capital Ships in the case of an engagement.</t><!-- a Shipyard built from pirated Parts to maintain Pirate Ships ( for the Fight against tenshi/god - pun to Angel Beats! intended :D :P ) -->
 <t id="1013">SSS</t>
 <t id="1014">SSS</t>
</page>


<!-- New NPC Voices generated via TTS for the Plot -->
<page id="10150" title="Argon NPC Male 5 / Misc Plot Characters" descr="0" voice="yes" espeak-options="-v en-5">
 <!-- Pages 200.000 to 500.000 are for Plot-use - will do the same -->
 <t id="200000" >Omicron Superyard Plot - Plot beginn: Offer to Map DeVries</t>
 <t id="200001" >The Canteran Government needs your Support once more. Please see me at the Crystal Castle for more Info.</t>


 <!-- Just to keep existing functionality -->
 <t id="0">[argon] [terran] male basic</t>
 <t id="1">Hey, my friend.</t>
 <t id="2">Hearing you loud and clear, pal.</t>
 <t id="3">I'll listen.</t>
 <t id="4">Not today thanks.</t>
 <t id="5">I'm really looking forward to this!</t>
 <t id="6">{,1}</t>
 <t id="11">You take care and look me up again.</t>
 <t id="12">Be good, mind!</t>
 <t id="13">I'll be watching!</t>
 <t id="14">Enough already!</t>
 <t id="15">It was really great helping out.</t>
 <t id="21">Do you think you can check for leaks as well?</t>
 <t id="22">Hey, does this mean we're best buddies now?</t>
 <t id="23">You'll get into trouble you naughty Pilot!</t>
 <t id="24">I hope this isn't the lead up to anything painful!</t>
 <t id="25">I'll go hide on the ship and you see if you can find me!</t>
 <t id="26">OK, you got me there. There's enough to go round you know!</t>
 <t id="31">OK, but can you do it from the port side? That's my better profile!</t>
 <t id="32">We see you are a bit of a nosey parker!</t>
 <t id="33">If that scan was a joke, it was a pretty silly action around here.</t>
 <t id="34">See the defences? They see you too!</t>
 <t id="35">Go ahead but excuse the mess; we haven't tidied up yet.</t>
 <t id="36">Well we could debate this all day, or you could name a price for your silence maybe!</t>
 <t id="37">Damn! I was sure they said it was only illegal in the other systems...</t>
 <t id="38">Are you sure? I cannot believe that the crew would allow something like that to be smuggled aboard.</t>
 <t id="39">Hmm, well maybe we could put it down to a scanner glitch? Yes?</t>
 <t id="41">My memory, it's awful these days. Sorry.</t>
 <t id="42">{,4}</t>
 <t id="50">Ha ha. I just laughed so much that I armed the defence systems by mistake!</t>
 <t id="51">I don't suppose I could ask you to surrender to me instead?</t>
 <t id="52">No problem. Let's get this done all nice and safely.</t>
 <t id="60">Look here is a sweetener for you to let me go.</t>
 <t id="61">I think a bit of dropped cargo could convince you to hold fire? Yes?</t>
 <t id="70">Ok, enough! I'm going swimming!</t>
 <t id="71">Ejecting now! Look after the old girl!</t>
 <t id="1000"></t>
 <t id="1001">Good to speak to you Sir.</t>
 <t id="1002">Lovely to meet you Sir.</t>
 <t id="1003">Hello Sir. How may I help?</t>
 <t id="1004">Hello Sir. You look even more distinguished in person!</t>
 <t id="1005">Until next time.</t>
 <t id="1006">It was my pleasure Sir.</t>
 <t id="1008">Signing off for now Sir.</t>
 <t id="1009">I am at your Service.</t>
 <t id="1010">I'm now in your squad.</t>
 <t id="1011">I'm leaving your squad. I'll miss them!</t>
 <t id="1012">Of course Sir.</t>
 <t id="1013">Be certain of it.</t>
 <t id="1014">Sorry Sir, that's beyond even my capabilities.</t>
 <t id="1015">That's not currently feasible.</t>
 <t id="1016">Automatic operations have commenced Sir.</t>
 <t id="1017">Naturally. I'll await your commands.</t>
 <t id="1018">Affirmative.</t>
 <t id="1019">Understood.</t>
 <t id="1020">Negative.</t>
 <t id="1021">Charging Jump Drive for new destination.</t>
 <t id="1022">Jump aborted!</t>
 <t id="1023">Counting down to jump.</t>
 <t id="1024">We are out of here! Jumping now!</t>
 <t id="1025">The Jump Drive is still on cool-down.</t>
 <t id="1026">Jump Drive charging.</t>
 <t id="1027">Jump achieved and all systems are in the green.</t>
 <t id="1028">Boosting to meet up with you, Sir.</t>
 <t id="1029">Boosters operating at full efficiency.</t>
 <t id="1031">We will stick close to you Sir.</t>
 <t id="1032">We're on our way to the coordinates.</t>
 <t id="1033">Moving to dock.</t>
 <t id="1034">Successfully docked.</t>
 <t id="1035">Task accomplished Sir.</t>
 <t id="1036">Got that. Proceeding as planned.</t>
 <t id="1037">We're in position, Sir.</t>
 <t id="1038">At location as ordered.</t>
 <t id="1040">It's great to be back with you, Sir.</t>
 <t id="1041">We're at your location now, Sir.</t>
 <t id="1045">OK, taking up guard position now.</t>
 <t id="1046">Sir, it's an honour to welcome you aboard.</t>
 <t id="1050">Err .. we don't have any drones for that task.</t>
 <t id="1051">We're short of those drones, but we'll use what few we have for as long as we can.</t>
 <t id="1052">Much as I'd like to do it myself, we need some more drones to do that.</t>
 <t id="1053">We need to restock our drones. We can't do much without the little chaps.</t>
 <t id="1054">Some more ships would be handy in this job, Sir.</t>
 <t id="1055">That's great! She'll be put to work straight away.</t>
 <t id="1056">That's incompatible with our current operations, Sir.</t>
 <t id="1057">We'll wind up our current operations now.</t>
 <t id="1058">We're ready for new instructions, Sir.</t>
 <t id="1059">Our licence agreement was just cancelled, Mr Otani.</t>
 <t id="1060">I'm sure you'll know the reasons why.</t>
 <t id="1070">Our ship is badly damaged but holding up for now. We'll need new orders.</t>
 <t id="1071">We can't move, even if I get out and push. We need assistance right here!</t>
 <t id="1072">Affirmative. We're on our way to the next shipyard. I'm looking forward to a decent shower!</t>
 <t id="1073">We're docked at the shipyard. Awaiting new orders - but the food here is great!</t>
 <t id="1074">Our Jump Drive is damaged. We're not jumping anywhere else without it.</t>
 <t id="1075">We'll jump as soon as we can. I don't intend to hang around here anymore than I have to.</t>
 <t id="1076">We've docked at the shipyard. Awaiting new orders while we get cleaned up.</t>
 <t id="1077">Our engine is damaged - we could only move by towing the old girl with an escape capsule.</t>
 <t id="1078">We'll move as soon as we can - at least the scenery is spectacular here!</t>
 <t id="1079">We'll do an emergency jump. See you on the other side - hopefully!</t>
 <t id="1080">Hurrah! Emergency jump successful - it's nice here. Awaiting new orders.</t>
 <t id="1081">Departing this zone now.</t>
 <t id="1082">We're safely in the new location and awaiting orders.</t>
 <t id="1090">We don't have enough fuel to jump that far.</t>
 <t id="1091">We need some extra fuel for that length of jump.</t>
 <t id="1092">Heading for the nearest fuel depot. We'll get the galley restocked too!</t>
 <t id="1093">We'll refuel and then do the ordered jump. A logical sequence really!</t>
 <t id="1094">A fuel tanker would be handy just now, we're out of jump juice!</t>
 <t id="1095">We're running dry on fuel and the refuel station is too far away. We need some resupply here.</t>
 <t id="1096">Attempting generator-powered jump since we don't have the fuel we need. Wish us luck!</t>
 <t id="1097">We're below the required energy stocks but we'll force a jump anyway. This should be interesting!</t>
 <t id="1098">Absolutely, Sir. We'll have to refuel before we can get there though.</t>
 <t id="1101">Hello Sir, Architect speaking. I've lots of suggestions for you.</t>
 <t id="1102">How would you like us to handle the provision of construction resources?</t>
 <t id="1103">All right, that is sufficient for now. Please confirm you want that station here since the construction runs on automatic once started.</t>
 <t id="1104">Your fine new module is complete Sir. What would you like next?</t>
 <t id="1105">Your station is ready Sir. It's magnificent!</t>
 <t id="1106">This is the next module on the build schedule Sir.</t>
 <t id="1107">Current progress dictates what modules may now be added. I'll show you what is available now.</t>
 <t id="1108">Are you sure this is the module you want? It's too late to change your mind once we start.</t>
 <t id="1109">What a grand plan! Construction will start immediately.</t>
 <t id="1110">Hello Sir, your Architect here. Your station in progress will need a Station Manager. Now would be a good time to find one and deliver them here.</t>
 <t id="1111">The stations available for construction are listed here. They're most impressive.</t>
 <t id="1112">Moving to the new construction site now.</t>
 <t id="1113">Hello Sir, you've a good eye for spaceships. What can we interest you in?</t>
 <t id="1114">We've all we need to proceed. Are you positive this ship is the one you want? Once we get going, the cost is payable in full.</t>
 <t id="1115">Ship construction complete Sir. She is breath-taking!</t>
 <t id="1116">Our construction list is currently full but if you check out our listings and call back later, then I am sure that we can satisfy your needs.</t>
 <t id="1117">Hello Sir. Concerning your fine ship in progress; she'll be needing a skilled pilot. Do you have anyone available or in mind?</t>
 <t id="1118">Here are ships we specialise in. Take your pick.</t>
 <t id="1119">We don't have enough funding, Sir.</t>
 <t id="1120">Check. Our funding is fine now, so let's get on with it.</t>
 <t id="1121">These are the extensions we provide. Some interact with each other and so you must bear that in mind.</t>
 <t id="1122">I would grateful if you'd set and confirm the upgrade levels.</t>
 <t id="1123">Set the repair percentage you want us to attain.</t>
 <t id="1124">Here are the station modules that we can add for you.</t>
 <t id="1125">I can show you my resource status in this display.</t>
 <t id="1126">Don't worry, any credits not needed will be returned to you in full.</t>
 <t id="1151">That's a fine deal, we're on our way to meet you.</t>
 <t id="1152">Preparing for receipt of wares.</t>
 <t id="1153">Delivery of wares imminent.</t>
 <t id="1154">I'm sorry, our cargo bay is full and we can't fit in even a Teladi contortionist!</t>
 <t id="1155">We'd need a different ship to transport that type of ware. I guess you won't buy me a bigger ship?</t>
 <t id="1156">Well we've been lucky and are already chock full! What shall we do instead?</t>
 <t id="1157">We can't get all that we wanted here. Tell you what, I'll buy what I can unless you've another plan</t>
 <t id="1158">It seems we have more than they want now. Want me to sell off what I can, or should I do something else?</t>
 <t id="1159">Well we're here, but they don't seem to have what we wanted. I'll press on to the next adventure, unless you've some orders for me.</t>
 <t id="1160">Yes, I know they must be insane, but they don't seem to want what we have to sell. Want me to go on with then next trade or have you something else in mind?</t>
 <t id="1161">They're charging a silly price here for what we wanted. I'll buy at that outrageous price if you want.</t>
 <t id="1162">I'll need some advice here. They won't pay our asking price. Shall I sell the load for peanuts anyway or what?</t>
 <t id="1163">That deal isn't going to happen here with the market as it is. What now?</t>
 <t id="1164">I seem to have a stack of lovely credits we have made for you. Shall I transfer the surplus to your account?</t>
 <t id="1165">That deal is all sewn up now. I'll send you a report of the details.</t>
 <t id="1166">We've arrived, so let's get trading!</t>
 <t id="1170">There, I told you I was a wizard with these things.</t>
 <t id="1171">Just like new at a fraction of the replacement price!</t>
 <t id="1172">See? It is all in knowing where and how hard to give it a bang!</t>
 <t id="1201">Ready to mine. Just give the word.</t>
 <t id="1202">Collectors on the way. Wish them good luck!</t>
 <t id="1203">Collectors being recalled. Let's see what they bring home.</t>
 <t id="1204">Automatic operations are running.</t>
 <t id="1205">That would challenge our ship. She needs a different cargo bay for that.</t>
 <t id="1206">Affirmative. Our drones will happily pick up whatever you tag for them.</t>
 <t id="1207">Affirmative. Our clever little drones can prioritize anything you tag.</t>
 <t id="1208">That's a no-go. We don't have the drones for that job.</t>
 <t id="1209">Of course. Our busy little drones will collect that up in no time.</t>
 <t id="1210">We have finished mining and will tag along with you - unless you've another task for us.</t>
 <t id="1211">We're full to the brim and returning to meet up with you.</t>
 <t id="1220">Hmm. I've just been hailed and told to drop my cargo!</t>
 <t id="1221">The markings suggest that it's a police ship.</t>
 <t id="1222">The ship is not acting at all friendly towards me.</t>
 <t id="1223">Should I just comply?</t>
 <t id="1300">_Documentation</t>
 <t id="1301">Waiting on standby for your next set of orders Sir.</t>
 <t id="1302">Analysing the data for the best point of attack.</t>
 <t id="1303">We'll drop down here and make that hull look like paper.</t>
 <t id="1304">Well in my best guess we might as well drop right there.</t>
 <t id="1305">Pod on the way.</t>
 <t id="1306">Hey, their fire is a bit too accurate for my taste!</t>
 <t id="1307">We're certainly earning marine-pay here!</t>
 <t id="1308">Starting to peel the hull open.</t>
 <t id="1309">Hull breached, let's take a look around inside!</t>
 <t id="1310">Team formed up and ready to exploit.</t>
 <t id="1311">We're moving up. Fingers on triggers.</t>
 <t id="1312">I've got movement here - lots of it!</t>
 <t id="1313">Contact!</t>
 <t id="1314">Scatter!</t>
 <t id="1315">Light them up!</t>
 <t id="1316">We're taking losses here!</t>
 <t id="1317">All-round defence!</t>
 <t id="1318">Get up and move forward!</t>
 <t id="1319">Covering fire! Hit them hard!</t>
 <t id="1320">Keep going!</t>
 <t id="1321">Hostiles ahead.</t>
 <t id="1322">Look at them run! Get up and follow!</t>
 <t id="1323">We're not seeing a withdrawal. We'll have to fight through.</t>
 <t id="1324">Sentries knocked out!</t>
 <t id="1325">Never mind, we'll deal with them the hard way!</t>
 <t id="1326">We're at a security outpost.</t>
 <t id="1327">Starting system hack.</t>
 <t id="1328">Automated defences neutralised.</t>
 <t id="1329">Well, that's a bummer. We'll take out the defences ourselves.</t>
 <t id="1330">Uh oh! That sounds like the self-destruct alarm! Get it hacked, now!</t>
 <t id="1331">Self-destruct sequence aborted.</t>
 <t id="1332">It's not working! Get out of here, pronto!</t>
 <t id="1333">We have control.</t>
 <t id="1334">Our losses are too heavy to continue. Fall back!</t>
 <t id="1335">This hull won't make it! Head for the pods!</t>
 <t id="1336">We're in the pods and on our way back.</t>
 <t id="1400">_Documentation</t>
 <t id="1401">I need a medic!</t>
 <t id="1402">Damn, that's a fine marine gone!</t>
 <t id="1403">Argh...</t>
 <t id="1404">Throwing stun!</t>
 <t id="1405">Throwing smoke!</t>
 <t id="1406">Get that hatch open! Fire in the hole!</t>
 <t id="1407">Marking priority targets!</t>
 <t id="1408">Get some fire on that corner!</t>
 <t id="1409">Clear to move!</t>
 <t id="1410">Laser turrets!</t>
 <t id="1411">Force field blocking the corridor.</t>
 <t id="1412">Force field disengaged!</t>
 <t id="1413">Now we need to find another route past it.</t>
 <t id="1414">They've given up, the ship is taken!</t>
 <t id="1415">They've no stomach for more, the station has surrendered!</t>
 <t id="1416">I don't think we're going to ma- -</t>
 <t id="1417">The target is well and truly ours. What a team!</t>
 <t id="1450">Upgrades installed and we're moving out.</t>
 <t id="1451">Downgrades completed. Moving now.</t>
 <t id="1452">Upgrades installed.</t>
 <t id="1453">Choose the ship for the upgrade.</t>
 <t id="1454">Which upgrade do you require changed?</t>
 <t id="1500"></t>
 <t id="1501">Did you know that you have someone doing my job already?</t>
 <t id="1502">You do have an Engineer on board at the moment.</t>
 <t id="1503">You have a Marine Officer on board already.</t>
 <t id="1510">Do you want me to replace them or will you find me another job?</t>
 <t id="1520">You'll never look back after hiring me Sir.</t>
 <t id="1521">My appointment will start a great partnership, Sir.</t>
 <t id="1530">I'm your new crew member. Where do I start?</t>
 <t id="1550">I'll leave at the next station stop-over. I'll be all right there.</t>
 <t id="1560">I'll leave immediately. Finding a new job won't be such a chore here.</t>
 <t id="1570">OK, Sir. I'll assume my new job immediately.</t>
 <t id="1571">Right. I'm in post now, Sir.</t>
 <t id="1575">OK, Sir. I'll be with you shortly.</t>
 <t id="1580">Wish me luck, Sir.</t>
 <t id="1581">Cheerio, try not to miss me!</t>
 <t id="1582">They don't come much more qualified than I am. Look here.</t>
 <t id="1583">These should impress you, I worked hard enough for them!</t>
 <t id="1600">Please let me have the new coordinates.</t>
 <t id="1610">That ship I sold has made you a tidy stack of credits.</t>
 <t id="1611">Sold as promised. I'll miss that dear old tub though.</t>
 <t id="1620">It's great that you trust me to do a good job on my own.</t>
 <t id="1621">I'll show that your trust in me is well-founded.</t>
 <t id="1630">I can play the good and loyal messenger. No worries there!</t>
 <t id="1631">OK. If you ever want me to use my own initiative, then just let me know.</t>
 <t id="2000"></t>
 <t id="2001">Waiting for an apology and a good explanation!</t>
 <t id="2002">Am I supposed to fire back as a big joke too?</t>
 <t id="2003">Do you feel like sharing what that was all about? Any time would be good!</t>
 <t id="2004">Press the wrong button there? I hope so for your sake!</t>
 <t id="2005">Aww .. and we've only just met. Such a shame!</t>
 <t id="2007">Now that was pretty silly. Any more and you'll be seeing lights - red and blue ones!</t>
 <t id="2008">I get it, you wanted attention. Well here come the police to give you some!</t>
 <t id="2009">Look, we're being attacked by a spacefly! </t>
 <t id="2010">I'm trying to watch a good vid here. Will you go away?</t>
 <t id="2011">Well that was ... unimpressive!</t>
 <t id="2012">That would make some pilots angry! Me, I'm just puzzled!</t>
 <t id="2013">I think this is a bit more serious!</t>
 <t id="2014">I've a real dog-fight here!</t>
 <t id="2015">I'm losing bits off my ship, and I think they matter!</t>
 <t id="2016">I would appreciate a bit of help before I end up walking home!</t>
 <t id="2017">This could be my final transmission! I want my Mummy now!</t>
 <t id="2018">Come in all assigned ships. This station is being attacked.</t>
 <t id="2019">We could do with some local deterrence here. Please report in.</t>
 <t id="2020">Our station has a problem. Attackers need seeing off.</t>
 <t id="2021">Aaagghhh!</t>
 <t id="2022">Nooooo!</t>
 <t id="2023">Aaarrrgghhh!</t>
 <t id="2031">Shields paper-thin!</t>
 <t id="2032">Shields marginal!</t>
 <t id="2033">Hull damage mounting!</t>
 <t id="2034">The hull is almost shot out!</t>
 <t id="2051">Well there's a sight, but not a good one!</t>
 <t id="2052">More coming! Don't give up yet!</t>
 <t id="2053">Get through these and we could be home and dry!</t>
 <t id="2054">Hello? Aren't you supposed to be over here helping me?</t>
 <t id="2055">They're done for. Good work everyone! There were a few close-calls there!</t>
 <t id="2056">Phew! That made them think again. Let's see what the cost has been.</t>
 <t id="2057">Short version - we lost badly.</t>
 <t id="2058">We came second by a long way!</t>
 <t id="2059">I'm in very poor shape here!</t>
 <t id="2060">Power is unstable and I can't hold her for long!</t>
 <t id="2061">Enemy targets on closing vectors!</t>
 <t id="2062">This looks ... ominous. I don't like it here!</t>
 <t id="2070">Can't you tell when a ship is out of the fight?</t>
 <t id="2071">Spare me and I'll become a Goner preacher!</t>
 <t id="2072">Listen my death is worthless to you, but my ship is worth a lot!</t>
 <t id="2073">This ship has given her all. Don't let her die as a cloud of glowing scrap!</t>
 <t id="2100">Follow our lead.</t>
 <t id="2101">Stick close, real close.</t>
 <t id="2102">We'll be your shadow.</t>
 <t id="2103">Lead on MacDuff.</t>
 <t id="2104">Ready when you are.</t>
 <t id="2105">Ready and waiting!</t>
 <t id="2200">Evacuation ordered. Follow your training and obey all orders.</t>
 <t id="3000"></t>
 <t id="3001">So, are you still up for this little adventure I've planned for you?</t>
 <t id="3002">You'll like this! Are you ready to set off?</t>
 <t id="3011">You can probably do this one on autopilot!</t>
 <t id="3012">The main hazard here might be boredom!</t>
 <t id="3013">I'm not sure you can do this. I hope you can prove me wrong!</t>
 <t id="3014">I've a lot riding on this and I don't like taking chances on greenhorns!</t>
 <t id="3015">This will be a doddle for gun-happy pilots like you.</t>
 <t id="3016">Yeah, I think you could be classed as overkill for this job!</t>
 <t id="3017">I see you are keen, but the keen ones usually end up dead!</t>
 <t id="3018">Not afraid eh? That sounds a bit like empty bravado to me!</t>
 <t id="3019">A simple job moving stuff. Even you couldn't mess this one up!</t>
 <t id="3020">You'll like this cargo-run. No hassle and no danger!</t>
 <t id="3021">I need a freight delivery made in the face of adversity. Are you good enough?</t>
 <t id="3022">You seem sure of yourself, but I'm not so sure!</t>
 <t id="3023">Had second thoughts?</t>
 <t id="3024">Still looking to make a name for yourself?</t>
 <t id="3031">OK, this could profit us both.</t>
 <t id="3032">Fair enough, we'll give it a go.</t>
 <t id="3033">Well, against my better judgement, go on then!</t>
 <t id="3034">I really, really hope I'm not making a big mistake!</t>
 <t id="3035">No sorry, I think it would end in grief for both of us.</t>
 <t id="3036">I think I'll wait for someone who seems more suitable for this.</t>
 <t id="3037">Your computer should have the information now.</t>
 <t id="3038">Check out the job details on your computer.</t>
 <t id="3041">Well done! That makes us both really happy - and richer.</t>
 <t id="3042">Good stuff! I felt you would bring me some good luck for a change.</t>
 <t id="3043">Was that it? Oh well, it's not a complete loss.</t>
 <t id="3044">I won't get rich on so-so jobs. I hope the next pilot is better.</t>
 <t id="3045">Why did you bother checking in? You've ruined me!</t>
 <t id="3046">What? You expect a pat on the back for that screw-up?</t>
 <t id="3047">Your lovely pile of credits is on its way.</t>
 <t id="3048">Here is a little extra by way of thanks for a good job.</t>
 <t id="3050">I'm afraid the client has pulled out. No job, sorry.</t>
 <t id="3051">Your briefing has been changed to meet new circumstances.</t>
 <t id="3052">Check out your briefing, there have been some updates.</t>
 <t id="3101">I want someone removed - forever, and ideally painfully.</t>
 <t id="3102">I want you to help someone to meet up with their parents again - their dead parents! </t>
 <t id="3103">You were sent to remove me in that crate? This is a joke right?!</t>
 <t id="3104">Don't spend your blood-money yet, you'll have to get me first!</t>
 <t id="3105">There could be something in it for you - if we both leave here alive!</t>
 <t id="3106">No-one could survive that!</t>
 <t id="3107">You lost them? Did they suddenly engage a cloaking device or something?</t>
 <t id="3108">You took their money over ours? That'll prove very costly for you!</t>
 <t id="3121">Hi, our defence forces could do with a hand just now. We have hostiles incoming and nowhere to send our civilians.</t>
 <t id="3122">Thin out the raiders due here any time now. We'll pay you for each kill you do.</t>
 <t id="3123">We're out-gunned here. Anyone, please help!</t>
 <t id="3124">Distress call! Help us survive continuing attacks by raiders. We can pay well.</t>
 <t id="3141">Smugglers operate in this area and we need an unfamiliar ship to get close enough to scan them. We pay well for information about such operations.</t>
 <t id="3142">That looks like excellent data and should lead to several arrests of ring-leaders.</t>
 <t id="3143">So there was nothing suspicious? Oh well. Perhaps they got wind of you.</t>
 <t id="3144">Well, since they have been boasting how they got their shipments through, I think you must've been asleep!</t>
 <t id="3161">I need a lift pretty much now. Can you help me out?</t>
 <t id="3162">I have to get to a destination rather quickly. Are you up to earning some credits?</t>
 <t id="3163">I'm snug and cosy back here.</t>
 <t id="3164">Yeah, funny! How am I supposed to fit in here with no room?</t>
 <t id="3165">Hello! I'm getting really bored back here. Any chance of getting there soon?</t>
 <t id="3166">I'll just hop out at the next stop and try to piece my business back together. Thanks for nothing!</t>
 <t id="3167">Starting on new assignment now Sir. Thank you for your faith in me.</t>
 <t id="3181">We need a good operator to deliver some freight for us. Is that up your street?</t>
 <t id="3182">We need a consignment of wares brought here. Does that appeal to you, my friend?</t>
 <t id="3183">Much as we want you to enjoy the scenery, we do have a deadline to meet!</t>
 <t id="3184">The wait here is killing us. Any chance you could hurry it up?</t>
 <t id="3185">Our reputation for prompt delivery just took a dive! Don't show your face around here again!</t>
 <t id="3186">Do what you want now. We'll find a reliable delivery service instead!</t>
 <t id="3500">I need assistance here! Please come back if you can help!</t>
 <t id="3501">I can make it well worthwhile for anyone receiving this who can help me out with a problem!</t>
 <t id="3502">Get here fast! Big problem! Big need! Big reward!</t>
 <t id="4001">Docking permission granted.</t>
 <t id="4011">Welcome aboard.</t>
 <t id="4012">Good to see you aboard.</t>
 <t id="4013">It is nice to have you visit us.</t>
 <t id="4020">Saving our station from those raiders was rather heroic.</t>
 <t id="4021">That's one we owe you, Skunk!</t>
 <t id="4022">Thanks 'Pride'. You got us out of a mess there.</t>
 <t id="4030">Your assistance was really appreciated. Here are your credits.</t>
 <t id="4100">Pilot, I've some great deals to offer!</t>
 <t id="4101">Hi, like what you see here?</t>
 <t id="4102">Great to see you. We try to cater for all needs here.</t>
 <t id="4103">Don't go anywhere else, we offer the best deals around.</t>
 <t id="4104">There's nothing shoddy nor sub-standard in my stock!</t>
 <t id="4105">This is what I have available for you.</t>
 <t id="4106">Let's get started.</t>
 <t id="4107">Nothing to hold us back now.</t>
 <t id="4110">A pleasure to do business.</t>
 <t id="4111">Accepted!</t>
 <t id="4119">{,4111}</t>
 <t id="4120">We can customise any of these weapons to fit in your ship.</t>
 <t id="4130">Ammo resupply should be up there with life-support maintenance in my opinion.</t>
 <t id="4131">Anyone leaving port without full ammunition bins is taking a big risk.</t>
 <t id="4140">We only stock the finest goods here!</t>
 <t id="4141">My rivals know that we beat them on quality and price.</t>
 <t id="4150">A fine choice, if I may say so.</t>
 <t id="4160">May I ask the quantity you want?</t>
 <t id="4170">Would you like to see anything else?</t>
 <t id="4180">We'll get this fitted to your ship.</t>
 <t id="4190">We'll take this over to your ship and get it in place.</t>
 <t id="4200">Pride of Albion, that's a great name for her after that work.</t>
 <t id="4201">We take pride in our modification work. She'll wear her name well after this.</t>
 <t id="4202">We've done a job that befits a lady with the name 'Pride of Albion'.</t>
 <t id="4210">I sense you don't mind taking a bit of a risk, if the money's right!</t>
 <t id="4211">I can do you a special deal on some very 'special' stuff!</t>
 <t id="4212">Let me know how much you can take without arousing too much suspicion.</t>
 <t id="4220">Ahah! Someone in the market for a licence, I believe.</t>
 <t id="4221">I can determine if you're suitable to be granted one of these licences.</t>
 <t id="4222">We remind customers that each licence imposes a degree of responsibility upon the owner.</t>
 <t id="4223">This licence permits you to further the interests of the issuing faction.</t>
 <t id="4300">Excellent!</t>
 <t id="4301">Bargain struck!</t>
 <t id="4302">Agreed.</t>
 <t id="4310">You have a deal!</t>
 <t id="4400">Hello, what seems to be the problem?</t>
 <t id="4401">You can count on us, whatever the need.</t>
 <t id="4410">Emergency! Help needed!</t>
 <t id="4411">Calling all ships, please respond!</t>
 <t id="4412">Is anyone out there? I need your help!</t>
 <t id="4413">Please open contact! I am in trouble here!</t>
 <t id="4420">Station command for unidentified ship.</t>
 <t id="4430">Station command for Ren Otani.</t>
 <t id="4440">We do not tolerate unprovoked attacks in our space.</t>
 <t id="4450">Your actions will not be tolerated here.</t>
 <t id="4460">You will regret doing that!</t>
 <t id="4461">We'll take you to task for that!</t>
 <t id="4470">Tell me that was not intended!</t>
 <t id="4471">That leads to a place where you don't want to go!</t>
 <t id="4480">Your cover has been blown!</t>
 <t id="4500">Station command for local authorities.</t>
 <t id="4510">We're sustaining heavy fire here.</t>
 <t id="4520">Please provide assistance.</t>
 <t id="4530">Be assured, we're sending forces now.</t>
 <t id="4540">We're already heavily engaged and don't have any forces to spare just now.</t>
 <t id="4550">You cannot be serious!</t>
 <t id="4551">I just don't believe it!</t>
 <t id="4560">Report related to individual Ren Otani.</t>
 <t id="4561">Sending file about Ren Otani.</t>
 <t id="4562">Sending file.</t>
 <t id="4570">On file.</t>
 <t id="4571">Don't we know him?</t>
 <t id="4572">Ah, that criminal!</t>
 <t id="4573">Data received.</t>
 <t id="4574">Not her again!</t>
 <t id="4575">Ah yes. We know of her.</t>
 <t id="4580">Contacting law enforcement.</t>
 <t id="4600">Hey! This is far too good to miss!</t>
 <t id="4601">Hi, this place can do you a really good deal!</t>
 <t id="4605">I've some leeway on price. Want a good discount?</t>
 <t id="4606">This offer is hurting me!</t>
 <t id="4610">We seem to have a healthy surplus of stock just now.</t>
 <t id="4611">We had some time-wasters bidding for stock.</t>
 <t id="4612">Our resource-buyer got a bit carried away.</t>
 <t id="4650">Sir, there's a delicate situation here.</t>
 <t id="4651">We have a dilemma that needs straightening out.</t>
 <t id="4660">Our station is prevented from working.</t>
 <t id="4661">Station operation is at a halt.</t>
 <t id="4670">The details are on the way...</t>
 <t id="4671">We need your advice ...</t>
 <t id="4680">Our resources don't meet the demand.</t>
 <t id="4681">Our resources can't meet the level of demand.</t>
 <t id="4690">We're completely full.</t>
 <t id="4691">All storage has been used up.</t>
 <t id="4700">We could do with a manager here.</t>
 <t id="4710">You can improve our operational capability with these options.</t>
 <t id="4711">If you want to make us more effective, then you have these options.</t>
 <t id="4720">We're suffering attacks and need support at this location!</t>
 <t id="4721">We need support forces here to deter ships that have engaged us!</t>
 <t id="4730">We can transfer goods to whomever you indicate.</t>
 <t id="4740">Which ware would that be?</t>
 <t id="4741">What is the intended ware?</t>
 <t id="4750">How much?</t>
 <t id="4760">What number?</t>
 <t id="4761">Specify the amount please.</t>
 <t id="4770">That's all in order. Commencing transfer.</t>
 <t id="4771">Transfer details acknowledged. Initiating.</t>
 <t id="4780">Are these items just for cargo, or to be mounted in the target itself?</t>
 <t id="4800">I've too few credits to proceed, I'm afraid.</t>
 <t id="4801">I can obtain the necessary credits from your account, unless you have other instructions.</t>
 <t id="4802">That has resolved the funding problem. We can proceed.</t>
 <t id="4803">I need to discuss my budget with you in the very near future, Sir.</t>
 <t id="4804">The budget changes are in force.</t>
 <t id="4910">Once we're in location, we'll start the operation.</t>
 <t id="4911">That can't be done at the moment. Sorry!</t>
 <t id="4912">What will be the mission after we arrive?</t>
 <t id="4913">Please identify our destination.</t>
 <t id="4914">Destination confirmed. We're on our way.</t>
 <t id="4915">We're at that location now. Please supply any further mission details.</t>
 <t id="4916">Our operation has commenced.</t>
 <t id="4917">Beginning of joint operation confirmed.</t>
 <t id="4920">Oh yes! I saw that happen in every nasty detail!</t>
 <t id="4921">I, err, suppose I could have, err, been mistaken. Yes?</t>
 <t id="4922">Oh, get real!</t>
 <t id="4930">Gosh! I never thought I'd get to meet a real local hero like you!</t>
 <t id="4931">You're the guy in all the newscasts. Well I never! What a great day for me!</t>
 <t id="4940">I can do this on my own, no problem! Unless you like me to take my other ships as back-up! What's it to be?</t>
 <t id="4950">I can go looking for job here. Unless you want me to stay on in another position, that is.</t>
 <t id="5000">Naturally Sir, where would you like to employ me?</t>
 <t id="5010">On my way to your location now. I'm looking forward to joining your fleet.</t>
 <t id="5011">Got that Sir! Moving now to join your command.</t>
 <t id="5020">I'm available for new tasking Sir. I will join your Squad until you decide.</t>
 <t id="5030">Sir? You've a ship assignment for me?</t>
 <t id="5040">I'll continue to comply with previous orders for now.</t>
 <t id="5050">Sir, this is what I am doing now.</t>
 <t id="5100">We do this hundreds of times every day. No need to get concerned over an official scan.</t>
 <t id="5101">Keep it calm and businesslike and our scan will be done in no time.</t>
 <t id="5102">Well, let's see what the shifty-looking pilot doesn't want us to find!</t>
 <t id="5103">We like seeing nervous pilots, but not so nervous that they make us nervous!</t>
 <t id="5110">There, all done. You can leave with our thanks for your time.</t>
 <t id="5111">We're finished thanks. Nothing to report means no paperwork. A win all round!</t>
 <t id="5112">I hate smug pilots. Get moving before I wipe that smirk off your face!</t>
 <t id="5113">You're a disappointment. I was sure we were on to something.</t>
 <t id="5120">This is the police. You're in breach of the local contraband regulations.</t>
 <t id="5121">Well, it seems we have an over-ambitious pilot. Just follow our orders and deal with this properly.</t>
 <t id="5122">Eject all contraband and we'll resolve this without any violence!</t>
 <t id="5130">We've hit pay-dirt! Look at that!</t>
 <t id="5131">See, I said he looked shifty and nervous!</t>
 <t id="5132">We can do this the hard and painful way, or you can drop some of the stuff. </t>
 <t id="5140">Well done. At least you got that bit right.</t>
 <t id="5141">That was the right thing to do. Now you can move along.</t>
 <t id="5142">Come now, you had more than that aboard.</t>
 <t id="5143">You didn't think we'd fall for that did you?</t>
 <t id="202000"></t>
 <t id="202001">This is Canteran Transport 23. Got some Reivers getting close and could do with some backup. En route to home base.</t>
 <t id="202002">I don't know who you are but we'd appreciate an escort. There are Reivers getting close. My people are on their way though, so no funny business.</t>
 <t id="202003">We need to get to friendly space safely. Watch our back and I'll be sure to get you a warm welcome.</t>
 <t id="202004">That's the way home up ahead. We should be safe enough on the other side.</t>
 <t id="202005">Thanks for the help. I'll try and clear you to dock at our home station.</t>
 <t id="202006">Otani! We're going to attempt to retrieve the life-pods but we could do with some covering fire.</t>
 <t id="302000"></t>
 <t id="302001">This is Plutarch security. Interceptors are on their way to your position. Shut down your engines and weapon systems.</t>
 <t id="302002">Your ship has been blacklisted. You should stand down.</t>
 <t id="402000"></t>
 <t id="402001">Lieutenant. We've got the civilian fleet covered. So far so good but aren't we spread a little thin right now. Heart of Albion now has to patrol two systems with half strength fleets.</t>
 <t id="402002">If you say so ma'am. Thanks ma'am.</t>
 <t id="402003">Additional ships incoming. Reivers!</t>
 <t id="402004">Plutarch and the Reivers have an alliance?</t>
 <t id="502001">Unknown vessel. We have a lock on your ship. Prepare to be escorted through the gate. This is your only warning.</t>
 <t id="900101">Now that strikes a deep chord with me!</t>
 <t id="900102">If only I were as adept with words as you are!</t>
 <t id="900103">We see so much eye-to-eye! It's uncanny!</t>
 <t id="900104">That's great news. We are so much of the same opinions!</t>
 <t id="900201">You know how to get your way don't you! Quite the orator!</t>
 <t id="900202">Wherever did you get such good information?</t>
 <t id="900203">Keep it up! I have never been so impressed.</t>
 <t id="900204">We could keep this up all night. I like a good chat!</t>
 <t id="900301">Continue please. I'm still paying attention.</t>
 <t id="900302">I get it. That's an unusual viewpoint though.</t>
 <t id="900303">Well it takes all sorts to have a good discussion.</t>
 <t id="900304">You need differing views to have a good debate.</t>
 <t id="900401">That's beginning to sound rather superficial to me.</t>
 <t id="900402">I have little idea what you are going on about.</t>
 <t id="900403">If you could hurry up please. I have other business.</t>
 <t id="900404">I don't think we're quite on the same chapter or page.</t>
 <t id="900501">I think you're nothing but a time-waster!</t>
 <t id="900502">I can see that you don't respect another's opinions.</t>
 <t id="900503">I think you made a mistake in talking to me!</t>
 <t id="900504">All right. We've finished this talk now!</t>
 <t id="901700">This conversation has been the highlight of my day! I like you!</t>
 <t id="901701">You've earned my respect during our chat.</t>
 <t id="901750">{,901700|901701}</t>
 <t id="901760">{,5}</t>
 <t id="901800">I know, I can tell you about a special offer on a station nearby. You'll find this interesting!</t>
 <t id="901801">Here are the details of someone looking for a job. I can personally vouch for them.</t>
 <t id="901802">If you're looking to hire a skilled professional, then I know just the person for you.</t>
 <t id="901803">Anything we trade from now on gets my personal discount. It's only available for special friends.</t>
 <t id="4000000">Canterans. Is it just me or do they sound Terran?</t>
 <t id="4000001">Why wouldn't I? We just don't know enough about them.</t>
 <t id="4110002">I'm not so sure. The Argon and Terran peoples didn't get on. Maybe it's the same with the Canterans.</t>
 <t id="4310002">Luxuries aren't something I've dabbled in, but hey, now you mention it, it's a great idea!</t>
 <t id="5000000">I dread to think what Plutarch will do with Xenon tech.</t>
 <t id="5000001">The prospect is truly terrifying. You too should be afraid.</t>
 <t id="5110002">Even if you can fight fire with fire, a Xenon fleet on the rampage is a frickin' big fire.</t>
 <t id="5120002">Haha, OK, I see what you're saying. I'm right there with you.</t>
 <t id="5210002">That's precisely what has me worried.</t>
 <t id="5500002">That's a dangerous path. Not least because we don't know if we'd be any better than PMC at harnessing Xenon tech.</t>
 <t id="6000000">AI this, AGI that... what's all the fuss?</t>
 <t id="6000001">Give it to me straight. It's about time I knew what it's all about.</t>
 <t id="6400002">OK, so let me get this straight AGI really aren't the bad guys or am I missing something?</t>
 <t id="6511002">That certainly explains a lot. I didn't know that it happened like that.</t>
</page>

</language>
